<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Biology Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Computational Biology Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Indexing in Python</title>
      <link>/blog/indexing-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/indexing-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Indexing is when you grab certain elements from a vector or list. It’s done a little differently in Python compared to R.First, let’s take a look at how indexing is done in R. I’ve made a list of my favorite fruits. I did this in reticulate so that I can access the same list in Python. Now, I’ll grab the second through fourth elements in the list in R:fruits &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;mango&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;apricot&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;nectarine&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;dragonfruit&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;kiwi&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;fig&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;raspberry&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;lychee&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;loquat&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;jackfruit&amp;quot;)fruits[2:4]## [1] &amp;quot;apricot&amp;quot; &amp;quot;nectarine&amp;quot; &amp;quot;dragonfruit&amp;quot;In R, the first element is at position 1, so positions 2 through 4 correspond to elements 2 through 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michelle Mao Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>About MeI am an incoming MS1 at UT Southwestern. After attending TAMS from 2015 to 2017, I graduated from the University of Texas at Austin in 2020 with a BS in Human Biology and a minor in Spanish. This website serves as a portfolio for my projects where I use R to analyze data that interests me. I am also interested in linguistics and worked with stroke and TBI survivors at Austin Speech Labs on their language recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe datasets I chose for this project are two datasets documenting the COVID-19 cases around the world (one dataset records cases in Hubei, China, while the other dataset records cases outside of Hubei), and one dataset with population data for every country. The COVID-19 datasets are updated live as new cases are confirmed, but for this project I am using data on the cases that were confirmed between 1/20/20 (the first cases that appear in the dataset) and 2/29/20 (the date I procured the dataset).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionFor this project, I am using an updated version of the COVID-19 dataset that I used for Project 1. This is an open-access dataset by the Emergent Epidemics Lab of Northeastern University that documents individual confirmed cases of COVID-19. It was originally updated as new cases were confirmed, but the researchers appear to have stopped recording on 3/31/20 (perhaps because it was no longer realistic to attempt to document every single case in the world once COVID-19 became a pandemic).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>